Come and get some!
Superbad is a comedy film directed by Greg Mottola.
Two co-dependent high school seniors are forced to deal with separation
anxiety after their plan to stage a booze-soaked party goes awry.
Seth, played by Jonah Hill.
Evan, played by Michael Cera.
Fogell, played by Christopher Mintz-Plasse.
Officer Slater, played by Bill Hader.
Officer Michaels, played by Seth Rogen.
Becca, played by Martha MacIsaac.
Superbad is a 2007 American coming-of-age teen buddy comedy film directed by Greg
Mottola, written by Seth Rogen and Evan Goldberg, and produced by Judd Apatow.
It stars Jonah Hill and Michael Cera as Seth and Evan, two
teenagers about to graduate from high school.
Before graduating, the boys want to party and lose their
virginity, but their plan proves harder than expected.
Christopher Mintz-Plasse (in his film debut), Rogen, Bill Hader, Martha
MacIsaac, and Emma Stone (in her film debut) provide supporting roles.
Rogen and Goldberg wrote the script during their teenage years.
It is loosely based on their experience in Grade 12 at Point Grey
Secondary School in Vancouver during the 1990s.
The main characters have the same given names as the two writers.
Rogen was also initially intended to play Seth, but due to age and physical size this was changed, and Hill went on to portray Seth,
while Rogen portrayed the irresponsible Officer Michaels, opposite Saturday Night Live star Hader as Officer Slater.
Superbad premiered at Grauman's Chinese Theatre on August 13, 2007, and was
theatrically released in the United States four days later on August 17, 2007.
The film received positive reviews, with critics praising the dialogue and the chemistry
between the two leads as well as the performances of the supporting cast.
The film also proved financially successful, grossing
$170.8 million on a $17.5–20 million budget.
The film has since become a cult classic, considered
among the best comedy films of all time.
The film explores themes of high school, police, alcohol, chaos, nerd.
The tone is lighthearted.